Experimental College Records UA044
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Experimental College Records
1967 -- 1997
1958 -- 2014
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Experimental College
Experimental College Board (Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Faculty)
UA044
38 Linear Feet 35 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized in four series: Subject files; Explorations and Perspectives; Course files; and Annual reports.
Biographical / Historical
Establishment, 1964-1968. The first board of the Experimental College was composed of faculty members representing four different fields: engineering, social science, natural science, and humanities, with one member-at-large. Almost immediately after convening, the board broke from Tufts tradition by including students in the decision-making process of the college. By the spring of 1966, the board unanimously agreed that its four student members be given full voting rights and that a two-thirds majority be required for all major decisions.
Among the students contributions were a movement toward the inclusion of ad hoc problem oriented courses in the curriculum, and the restructuring of the traditional classroom to include peer teaching. It was also at the suggestion of a student board member that the Ex College invited its first visiting lecturer to teach at Tufts.
Student Activism, 1969-1973. Relevance in the classroom, a key demand in the student rhetoric of the sixties, conjures images of gradeless classes, courses on consciousness, and open classrooms. In the Ex College, relevance in the classroom was funneled into an explosion of peer-led classes and courses on contemporary political issues. Its flexibility and openness made it an ideal place to absorb students political activity and demand for academic alternatives. The universitys African American Studies and Womens Studies programs were started in the Experimental College during this period, as was one of its most successful innovations, Explorations, a student-led seminar program that combines advising and academics for entering students, initiated in 1972.
The Struggle for a Permanent Charter, 1974-1979. By 1974, the Experimental College continued to display a capacity for growth and innovation. From its first course on the contemporary European novel to interdisciplinary science courses, to womens studies classes, to seminars on communications and law, the Ex College was able to adapt to a changing student culture. It was through this strength that the Ex College won a permanent charter in 1979. An outside evaluating committee reached the conclusion that for the Experimental College "to have survived and flourished as an innovative, undergraduate educational enterprise was nothing short of remarkable."
Growth and Change, 1979-1993. Along with continuing to emphasize Tufts commitment to undergraduate education through the testing of new ideas and courses, after 1979 the mission of the college took an important turn: developing and housing programs that did not fit well in the regular curriculum. Thus, the new charter meant that the Ex College -- along with testing such courses as American Sign Language, Arabic, Chinese, Hebrew, ethnomusicology, and jazz -- was now viewed as the appropriate venue for housing curricular innovations. This led to a decision on the part of the board to offer a special course intended to promote honest dialogue on campus, Race Awareness Within American Society. Moreover, the first two of a number of multidisciplinary programs, Peace and Justice Studies and Communications and Media Studies, were established as satellite programs. In 1990 the faculty approved independent status for Peace and Justice Studies, and it is now a major.
The attempt to have a positive impact on campus culture energized a group of student-friends of the Ex College who formed ACOIL (Advisory Committee on Intellectual Life), intended to foster the ideal of challenging oneself. Out of ACOIL grew EPIIC (Education for Public Inquiry and International Citizenship), yet another successful program, and now part of the Institute for Global Leadership.
The direction the Ex College embarked upon after 1979 hearkened back to the theme of its original charter: enhancing the undergraduate curriculum. In this spirit, the Ex College expanded its first-year programming during 1988 to include Perspectives, an alternative to the award-winning Explorations program. In 1991, the Ex College Board approved a proposal to make the program full-credit and base it on a survey of the movies as business and art.
Media, Technology, and the Future. In 1996, the Communications and Media Studies program, while continuing to be housed in the Ex College, won approval as an interdisciplinary minor. At almost the same time, the university embarked on a wiring project in the residence halls which, in turn, opened up the opportunity for educational access television on campus. After a three-year process of negotiation and study by the faculty, TUTV, the student-run, campus TV station, became another member of the Ex College family.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains files from the administrative office of the Experimental College. Subject files include general administrative and project topics including early board meeting minutes. Both Series 2 Explorations and Perspectives and Series 3 Courses files contain material pertaining to course content and instructors, and may include syllabi, reading lists, course descriptions, and student's application forms to take the course. Annual reports are available from 1970 through 1996.
Content Warning
This finding aid contains language that may be offensive or outdated. Because such language is in titles or direct transcription of published materials, it has not been changed. Keeping this language intact provides the most accurate depiction of the creators' intent, and can potentially tell us important things about bigotry and bias on the part of the creators, or in a particular historical context. It can also preserve terms formerly applied by a group to self-identify that have since fallen out of common usage. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
Tufts University -- History; Curriculum and Instruction -- Faculty; Curriculum and Instruction; Curriculum and Instruction -- Course Material; Experimental College
- Subject files, 1958 -- 2014; UA044.001; 9.85 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains office files of the Experimental College administration. It includes primarily committee minutes of the Ex-College Advisory Board as well as other files documenting special events and programs such as "Communications Cluster" special events, the 50th Ex-College Anniversary, internships, and orientation.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged roughly alphabetically through box 20; box 31 is arranged in received order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - [Committee on the Ex. College, Minutes], 1965 -- 1969; UA044.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1960 -- 1968; UA044.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Presidents Committee on Innovations and Experiments, 1962; UA044.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos, 1963; UA044.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Presidents Commitee on Experiment and Innovation, 1963; UA044.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos, 1964; UA044.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes, 1964; UA044.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Committee on the Experimental College, 1964; UA044.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Experimental College Faculty Minutes, 1965 -- 1969; UA044.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Memos and Reports, 1965; UA044.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Memos and Reports, 1965; UA044.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Committee on the Experimental College Minutes, 1965; UA044.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1966; UA044.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Board Minutes Jan 5- Jan 7, 1966; UA044.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1967; UA044.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos, 1966; UA044.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1967; UA044.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos, 1967; UA044.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1968; UA044.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1968; UA044.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting Minutes, 1969; UA044.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1969; UA044.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1969; UA044.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1969; UA044.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1969 -- 1970; UA044.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Memos, 1970; UA044.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes Jan- April, 1970; UA044.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Minutes: Board Meeting Summer, 1970; UA044.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes: Sept - December, 1970; UA044.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1970 -- 1971; UA044.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1971 -- 1972; UA044.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Old Ex- Course Documents, 1964 -- 1971; UA044.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - John Fersterwald, 1970 -- 1971; UA044.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Harry Ritchie, 1971; UA044.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Alan Orenstein, 1972; UA044.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Bruce Reitman, 1971 -- 1972; UA044.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, Jan- May, 1971; UA044.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, Summer, 1971; UA044.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes Sept-December, 1971; UA044.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1972; UA044.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Colloquia: Spring, 1972; UA044.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Explorations, 1972 -- 1973; UA044.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes- Sept- December, 1972; UA044.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - News Clipping, 1972 -- 1973; UA044.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1973; UA044.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1973; UA044.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1974; UA044.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1974; UA044.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1975; UA044.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1975; UA044.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Articles, 1974 -- 1975; UA044.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Video Proposal, 1974; UA044.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Reasorce Center Planning Committee, 1975 -- 1976; UA044.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - News Clippings, 1975 -- 1976; UA044.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Colloquia, 1975; UA044.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes Feb- May, 1976; UA044.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1977 -- 1978; UA044.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Board Meetings, 1976 -- 1977; UA044.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - News Clippings, 1976 -- 1977; UA044.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Liberal Conference Recommendation, 1977 -- 1978; UA044.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Colloquia, 1977 -- 1978; UA044.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - University Projects-, 1978; UA044.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - QUIDNUNC, UA044.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Experimental College Council, 1964 -- 1974; UA044.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Network, 1985 -- 1987; UA044.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Career Counciling, 1970; UA044.001.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Energy, 1979; UA044.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Legal Studies, 1979; UA044.001.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1979 -- 1980; UA044.001.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Other Experimental College Programs and Alternative Education Programs [1/3], 1972 -- 1988; UA044.001.002.00036 (Box 2)
  - Other Experimental College Programs and Alternative Education Programs [2/3], 1973; UA044.001.002.00037 (Box 2)
  - Other Experimental College Programs and Alternative Education Programs [3/3], 1988; UA044.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Old Posters [1/2], 1977; UA044.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Old Posters [2/2], 1977; UA044.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Various Old Mechanicals, 1977; UA044.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Communications Cluster, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Participants, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Report to the Faculty: October 29, 1982; UA044.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Attendence Lists: 1982-1983. Communications Cluster Mtgs., UA044.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Communication Cluster Correspondence, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Survey re: Special Activities for the Communications Cluster March, 1983; UA044.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Student Organizations, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Communications Curriculum: Proposed Courses, minutes, of Subcommitee Meetings, etc., 1981 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Communications Task Force, 1979; UA044.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Communication Cluster Minutes and Meeting notes, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Communication Cluster Special Events 1982-1983: Martin Linsky (presentation), UA044.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Communications Cluster Special Events, 1982-1983. AV Westin (presentation), UA044.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events, 1982-1983.Former Tufts Observer Editors, 11/14/82., UA044.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Chervinsky/Guilmartin (presentation), UA044.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Paul Lowenwater (presentation), UA044.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Comm. Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Vietnam Vets photo Documentarywith Leslie Major. (presentation), UA044.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Jack Valenti., UA044.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Fred Moriz. (Presentation), UA044.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Kathryn Tolbert Presentation., UA044.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Tony Benis presentation., UA044.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983. Paul Rich presentation., UA044.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Spec. Events 1983 TUTV's "Matrix" December, UA044.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Com Cluster Special Events Fall 1983 Jerry Chervinsky & Ron Brian "The Boston Elections & the Media" - Nov. 21, UA044.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events Fall 1983 Phillip Martin: Grenada: The Media & Public Opinion, Nov. 17, UA044.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events Fall 1983 Robert Chrisman, "Mass Media & Imperialism Nov. 22, UA044.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Student Meeting, Nov. 14, 1983; UA044.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Comm Clusters Special Events Fall 83 Tom Steel "cable TV:" Sports, Sex and Censorship Nov. 7, 1983; UA044.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Comm. Cluster Special Events Fall 1983 Meeting Re. Internships in Broadcasting Publishing and Advertising Oct 31, UA044.001.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - Comm. Cluster Special Events 1982-1983 Student Meeting, Oct. 11, UA044.001.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events Fall 83 "The Candidate" Oct. 13, 1983; UA044.001.003.00034 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events 1982-1983 Dukakis Press Conference Boston 10/3/83, UA044.001.003.00035 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events (Fall 1983) "Videodance" Program 9/28/83, UA044.001.003.00036 (Box 3)
  - Comm. Cluster 1982-83 "Legal and Ethical Issues in Broadcasting and the New Electronic Media" Spring 1983, Exp 54 CS, UA044.001.003.00037 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster, Spring, 1983; UA044.001.003.00038 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster Special Events (1982-83) Comm. Related Courses (1982-83), 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00039 (Box 3)
  - Comm Cluster 1982-83 People involved with the Cluster, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.003.00040 (Box 3)
  - Comm Interns, Fall, 1984; UA044.001.003.00041 (Box 3)
  - Communications Interns, Spring, 1985; UA044.001.003.00042 (Box 3)
  - Comm. Interns, Spring, 1984; UA044.001.003.00043 (Box 3)
  - Computer Services (Bob Curran), 1982; UA044.001.003.00044 (Box 3)
  - Proposal to NEH re. Film study and Consulting Grant, 1978; UA044.001.003.00045 (Box 3)
  - Tufts-MIT Campus Exchange, 1983 -- 1984; UA044.001.003.00046 (Box 3)
  - Tufts-MIT Campus Exchange, 1982 -- 1985; UA044.001.003.00047 (Box 3)
  - Technology Studies Program: Wellesley College, 1984 -- 1985; UA044.001.003.00048 (Box 3)
  - Hall-Hoag Collection, 1986; UA044.001.003.00049 (Box 3)
  - Library of Congress, 1985; UA044.001.003.00050 (Box 3)
  - Silha Center for the Study of Media Ethics & Law, 1984; UA044.001.003.00051 (Box 3)
  - Newsday Job Conference for Minority Students, 1985; UA044.001.003.00052 (Box 3)
  - CBS News Summer Interns, 1985; UA044.001.003.00053 (Box 3)
  - Cluster Brochure, 1984; UA044.001.003.00054 (Box 3)
  - Campus Media Brochure, 1986; UA044.001.003.00055 (Box 3)
  - Mailing Matrices, 1985 -- 1986; UA044.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Film Controls & Awards, 1984; UA044.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Student Addresses and Phone Numbers, 1986 -- 1987; UA044.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Memos, 1985 -- 1986; UA044.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - ABC Internship, 1986; UA044.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Tufts Cable: Memos and Proposals, 1979 -- 1982; UA044.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Museum of Broadcasting, New York, 1985; UA044.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - The Livingston Awards, 1984 -- 1985; UA044.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Move in Miner Hall, 1985; UA044.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Memos, 1986 -- 1987; UA044.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Reports about Communications Cluster, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Advising - Misc. Nov., 1986; UA044.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Acceptance Registration S1981, UA044.001.017.00001 (Box 17)
  - Admissions Bulletin Copy, 1983 -- 1984; UA044.001.017.00002 (Box 17)
  - Applied Physics Department, 1971; UA044.001.017.00003 (Box 17)
  - Advisory Board Meeting Oct. 6, 1983; UA044.001.017.00004 (Box 17)
  - Advisory Board Meeting Feb. 16, 1984; UA044.001.017.00005 (Box 17)
  - Adv. Bd. Mgt. -Film Sept. 26, 1984; UA044.001.017.00006 (Box 17)
  - Advisory Board Mtg. Nov. 15, 1984; UA044.001.017.00007 (Box 17)
  - Advisory Board Mtg. Feb. 28, 1985; UA044.001.017.00008 (Box 17)
  - Advisory Board Mtg. May 5, 1986; UA044.001.017.00009 (Box 17)
  - African American Center (Capen House), 1983; UA044.001.017.00010 (Box 17)
  - Spring 1983 VL Ballots, UA044.001.017.00011 (Box 17)
  - Communications Consultant #526561 National Endowment for Humanities, 1977; UA044.001.017.00012 (Box 17)
  - Com Clus Annual Report, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.017.00013 (Box 17)
  - Communications Cluster Notes, 1983; UA044.001.017.00014 (Box 17)
  - Ascent of Man Fall, 1975; UA044.001.017.00015 (Box 17)
  - Alternate-Community Elem. School, 1972; UA044.001.017.00016 (Box 17)
  - Alternate Highschool Programs, 1970; UA044.001.017.00017 (Box 17)
  - Arts Festival S, 1971; UA044.001.017.00018; Reitman, Bruce; Turok, Debbie (Box 17)
  - Antioch College Dec., 1966; UA044.001.017.00019 (Box 17)
  - Audio Visual Committee, 1976; UA044.001.017.00020 (Box 17)
  - Bicentennial Programs, 1976; UA044.001.017.00021 (Box 17)
  - Board Applic. Fall, 1983; UA044.001.017.00022 (Box 17)
  - Board Applications, 1981; UA044.001.017.00023 (Box 17)
  - Black Studies, 1981; UA044.001.017.00024 (Box 17)
  - Black Studies, 1970; UA044.001.017.00025 (Box 17)
  - Boston College Experimental College, 1969; UA044.001.017.00026 (Box 17)
  - Boston Univesity, 1966; UA044.001.017.00027 (Box 17)
  - Brandeis - Free University, 1967; UA044.001.017.00028 (Box 17)
  - Spring 1986 Explorations, UA044.001.017.00029; Cacciola, Debbie (Box 17)
  - Communication Program Fall, 1972; UA044.001.017.00030 (Box 17)
  - Accept/Reject adn "Follow Up" Notes and Models OLD, 1982; UA044.001.017.00031 (Box 17)
  - Bookstore Trensactions FY 82/83 208130, 1982; UA044.001.017.00032 (Box 17)
  - Budget Corr., 1984 -- 1985; UA044.001.017.00033 (Box 17)
  - Budget Doc's Notes, Misc. FY, 1983 -- 1984; UA044.001.017.00034 (Box 17)
  - Budget Mat'ls-Misc. FY, 1981 -- 1982; UA044.001.017.00035 (Box 17)
  - Budget Projection/New Directions, UA044.001.017.00036 (Box 17)
  - Colby College January Plan, 1961; UA044.001.017.00037 (Box 17)
  - College Within, 1971; UA044.001.017.00038 (Box 17)
  - College Within, 1972; UA044.001.017.00039 (Box 17)
  - Combined Bachelor's and Master's Degrees Program, 1968; UA044.001.017.00040 (Box 17)
  - Computer Center Etc., 1974; UA044.001.017.00041; Ritchie, Margaret (Box 17)
  - Communication Arts, 1975; UA044.001.017.00042 (Box 17)
  - Communication Arts Report, 1972; UA044.001.017.00043; Reitman, Bruce; Ritchie, Margaret (Box 17)
  - Community Open Courses, 1973; UA044.001.017.00044 (Box 17)
  - Community Teaching Program, 1973; UA044.001.017.00045 (Box 17)
  - Commuter Problems, 1974; UA044.001.017.00046 (Box 17)
  - Craft Center, 1977; UA044.001.017.00047 (Box 17)
  - Check Voucher Transaction Documentation FY 82/83 208130, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.017.00048 (Box 17)
  - Communications Cluster Transactions-Documentation FY, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.017.00049 (Box 17)
  - Course Descriptions -S, 1985; UA044.001.017.00050 (Box 17)
  - Course Selection Process Ex Coll Board, 1984; UA044.001.017.00051 (Box 17)
  - CETA, 1979; UA044.001.017.00052 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1978 -- 1979; UA044.001.017.00053 (Box 17)
  - Committee and Pre Course related evaluations, 1979; UA044.001.017.00054 (Box 17)
  - Course Evaluation Procedures, 1982; UA044.001.017.00055 (Box 17)
  - Courses-Teaching Spring, 1979; UA044.001.017.00056 (Box 17)
  - Spring Explorations II Current File, 1987; UA044.001.017.00057 (Box 17)
  - Dale's Plan of Study, 1976; UA044.001.017.00058 (Box 17)
  - Dance Miner, 1970; UA044.001.017.00059 (Box 17)
  - Dance, 1971; UA044.001.017.00060 (Box 17)
  - Dance Program, 1971; UA044.001.017.00061 (Box 17)
  - Descriptions, etc. Spring, 1985; UA044.001.017.00062 (Box 17)
  - Education Research, Experimentation and Development, UA044.001.017.00063 (Box 17)
  - Educational Reform - Edcentric Center for Educational Reform, 1969; UA044.001.017.00064 (Box 17)
  - Experimental College Committee Self-Achievement, 1968; UA044.001.017.00065 (Box 17)
  - Explorations Fall, 1985; UA044.001.017.00066 (Box 17)
  - Ex College Miscellany, 1982; UA044.001.017.00067 (Box 17)
  - Exp 95 (F,S) Short term Studies Correspondence, 1986; UA044.001.017.00068 (Box 17)
  - Effort Distribution Manuals, 1982; UA044.001.018.00001 (Box 18)
  - Effort Reporting Docs. FY, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.018.00002 (Box 18)
  - Effort Reporting Matl's., 1983; UA044.001.018.00003 (Box 18)
  - Evaluation Subcomms for S/85, 1985; UA044.001.018.00004 (Box 18)
  - Ex. Coll. Course -Proposal Log Book, 1984; UA044.001.018.00005 (Box 18)
  - Ex. Coll. Fund Transactions Documentation FY, 1982 -- 1983; UA044.001.018.00006 (Box 18)
  - Ex. Coll. Personal Documents (Inactive Records) - Staff, 1982; UA044.001.018.00007 (Box 18)
  - Experimental College Committee Freshman Seminar, 1969; UA044.001.018.00008 (Box 18)
  - Freshman Explo Background and Hist. Mat'ls, 1977; UA044.001.018.00009 (Box 18)
  - Experimental College Data, 1976; UA044.001.018.00010 (Box 18)
  - Explorations, Fall, 1982; UA044.001.018.00011 (Box 18)
  - Explos. Fall, 1984; UA044.001.018.00012 (Box 18)
  - Explorations Fall, 1987; UA044.001.018.00013 (Box 18)
  - Explorations II, 1987; UA044.001.018.00014 (Box 18)
  - Explorations F, 1988; UA044.001.018.00015 (Box 18)
  - Explorations Student - Leaders Fall, 1988; UA044.001.018.00016 (Box 18)
  - Explorations Fall 1988 Faculty Participants-Summer Address, UA044.001.018.00017 (Box 18)
  - Explo. Faculty Advisors List F'88, 1988; UA044.001.018.00018 (Box 18)
  - Explorations -Fall 1988 Faculty Participants -Local Address, UA044.001.018.00019 (Box 18)
  - Explorations Info F'86, 1986; UA044.001.018.00020 (Box 18)
  - Exploration Leaders Fall, 1986; UA044.001.018.00021 (Box 18)
  - Exploration Leaders Letters F'89, 1989; UA044.001.018.00022 (Box 18)